Guide to the Nancy Ottmann Albert Papers, 1981 - 2006
Nancy Ottmann Albert Papers1981 - 2006
Special Collections & Archives, Wesleyan University
Nancy Ottmann Albert
2014-33
12
31 archival containers
Albert began what would become the New England mill project in August of 1981, as a solo endeavor. Largely based on her own reading and library research, she aimed "to find and photograph every extant textile mill in southern New England." She photographed mills in Connecticut, Massachusetts, and Rhode Island. Her works also includes photographs of mental hospitals and images taken in New England, New York state, France, Cuba, Portugal, Spain, London, Italy, Eastern Europe, Vienna, Barcelona, Bosnia, Slovenia, Croatia, and Berlin.
The papers consist of research notes, negatives, slides, and photographs (both mounted and unmounted).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisitions Information
Donated by Nancy Ottmann Albert.
Biographical Note
Nancy Ottmann Albert received her Bachelor's Degree from Trinity College in 1988 and her Masters of Arts in Liberal Studies from Wesleyan University in 1994.
Albert began what would become the New England mill project in August of 1981, as a solo endeavor. Largely based on her own reading and library research, she aimed "to find and photograph every extant textile mill in southern New England." Living in western Connecticut at the time, she initially photographed Connecticut area mills, eventually moving outward to the Connecticut River Valley area as well as Rhode Island. As a child, she had lived in Holyoke, Massachusetts, and this connection led her to do particularly extensive work in that location.
Throughout the next few years, Albert expanded her project to include eastern Massachusetts, New Hampshire, and southern Maine. In 1984 she enrolled as an IDP student at Trinity College in Hartford, majoring in American studies. The Individualized Degree Program offered by Trinity enrolls adults not of college age looking to continue their education. For her undergraduate thesis at Trinity, she wrote a study of the company town of North Grosvenordale, Connecticut.
For her IDP project she completed a photo exhibition of industrial landscapes in New England. She graduated from Trinity in 1988 and started work at Wesleyan's Center for the Arts the next year. At Wesleyan, she began to take classes in the Graduate Liberal Studies Program.
In 1991, she became interested in the photography of Eugene Atget, a French flaneur at the turn of the century who is often considered a documentary photography pioneer given his attempts to capture the architecture and urban landscape of Paris before it succumbed to modernity. That same year, she took her first trip to Paris, following it up with a summer semester in the city in 1992 as a part of her GLSP work.
Under the direction of architecture professor John Martin, Albert completed a thesis on Atget's photography and Paris architecture, which included an exhibition at Wesleyan's Zilkha Gallery, in 1993. The next year she received her Masters of Arts in Liberal Studies.
From 1993 to 2004, Albert worked with the Hartford Studies Project at Trinity under the direction of Susan Pennybacker and photographed Hartford neighborhoods extensively. Additionally, she curated several photographic exhibitions at the Hartford Public Library and Trinity College. In 1998, Albert revisited the Milltown project in order to document the changes of the past 15 years.
In 1999, Albert was hired by the Middletown Housing Authority to document the demolition of Long River Village, Middletown's oldest housing project. Also that year, she finished documenting the changes of milltowns and began photographing mental hospitals with Sandra Wheeler.
From 2000 to 2005, Albert worked on both solo and group exhibitions and explored roadside and vernacular architecture. In 2001, she traveled to Havana, Cuba, where she photographed street life. The next year, she started work as a photo editor for the Hog River Journal, which she continued until 2005, when she was hired by Wesleyan to document the buildings at Long Lane School prior to demolition.
In 2006, Albert moved out of New England to Charlotte, North Carolina, where she began an ongoing exploration of North Carolina historic and vernacular architecture.
In addition to the subjects described above, Albert's work includes images taken in the New England, New York state, Portugal, Spain, London, Italy, Eastern Europe, Vienna, Barcelona, Bosnia, Slovenia, Croatia, and Berlin.
Collection Overview
The Nancy Ottmann Albert Papers are extensive. The majority of the materials consist of developed photographs and negatives. Research files on the New England places she photographed include a variety of documents and negatives. The research collection and negatives are organized by state and town. Photographs are generally organized by date range and area, but the photos within the boxes may be mixed.
Collection Arrangement
Series I: Research notes
Series II: Negatives
Series III: Slides
Series IV: Photographs
Online Catalog Headings
These and related materials may be found under the following headings in online catalogs.
Albert, Nancy Ottmann.; Photographs.; Slides.; Architecture--New England.; Factories--New England--Pictorial works.; Pyschiatric hospitals--New England--Pictorial works.; Paris (France)--Pictorial works.; Portugal--Pictorial works.; Spain--Pictorial works.; London (England)--Pictorial works.; Italy--Pictorial works.; Cuba--Pictorial works.; Vienna (Austria)--Pictorial works.; Barcelona (Spain)--Pictorial works.; Slovenia--Pictorial works.; Croatia--Pictorial works.; New England--Pictorial works.; Connecticut--Pictorial works.; Vermont--Pictorial works.; Massachusetts--Pictorial works.; Rhode Island--Pictorial works.; New Hampshire--Pictorial works.; Maine--Pictorial works.; New York (State)--Pictorial works.
Related Material
Long Lane Photographs Collection, Special Collections & Archives, Wesleyan University
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Series I. Research notes
  - Baltic, CT; Beacon Falls, CT; Brooklyn, CT (Box 1, Folder 1)
    C-B-1 Baltic, CT, Baltic Cotton Mill, 1900
    C-B-2 Beacon Falls CT, Home Woolen Mill 1865
    C-B-3 Brooklyn CT, Quinebaug Co. 1854
  - Wauregan, CT; Waterbury, CT (Box 1, Folder 2)
    C-W-1 Wauregan CT, Wauregan CT, 1853
    C-W-5 Waterbury CT, American Suspender Mills, 1843
  - Taftville, CT (Box 1, Folder 3)
    C-T-1 Taftville CT, Ponemah Mills, 1866
  - Manchester, CT (Box 1, Folder 4)
    C-M-4 Manchester CT, Cheny Brothers Silk Mills, 1865
  - Danielson, CT; East Hampton, CT; East Killingly, CT (Box 1, Folder 5)
    C-D-1a Danielson CT, Quinebaug Co., 1868
    C-E-1 East Hampton CT, Summit Thread Mills, 1880
    C-E-2b East Killingly CT, Elliotville Lower Mill (Peep Toad Mill), 1850
  - Norwich, CT (Box 1, Folder 6)
    C-N-3 Norwich CT (Yantic), Williams Flannel Mill, 1865
    C-Y-1a Norwich CT. (Yantic), Falls Company Mills, 1840
  - Putnam, CT (Box 1, Folder 7)
    C-P-1 Putnam CT, Pomfret Cotton Mills, 1824
    C-P-1a Putnam CT, Monohansett Mill, 1868
    C-P-1b Putnam CT, Rhodes Mill, 1841
    C-P-1c Putnam CT, Morse Mill, 1846
  - Putnam, CT; Amesbury, MA; Adams, MA; Ballardvale, MA (Box 1, Folder 8)
    C-P-1d Putnam CT, Powhatan Mill, 1872
    M-A-1 Amesbury MA, Hamilton Woolen Co., 1825
    M-A-2 Adams MA, Mill
    M-B-1 Ballardvale MA, Ballardvale Woolen Mills, 1835
  - Chicopee, MA (Box 1, Folder 9)
    M-C-1 Chicopee MA, Lyman Mill, n/d
  - East Douglas, MA; Gilbertville, MA (Box 1, Folder 10)
    M-E-1 East Douglas MA, mill
    M-G-1 Gilbertville MA, mill
    M-G-1a Gilbertville MA, mill
  - Fall River, MA (Box 1, Folder 11)
    M-F-1 Fall River MA, Richard Borden Mill, 1870
    M-F-1a Fall River MA, Chase Mill, 1872
    M-F-1b Fall River MA, Merchants Mill, 1867
    M-F-1d Fall River MA, Durfee Mills, 1866
    M-F-1e Fall River MA, Davol Mills, 1867
  - Grafton, MA; Hinsdale, MA; Housatonic, MA (Box 1, Folder 12)
    M-G-1 Grafton MA, mill
    M-H-2 Hinsdale MA, mill
    M-H-3 Housatonic MA, monument mills
  - Holyoke, MA (Box 1, Folder 13)
    M-H-1 Holyoke MA, Merrick Thread Co., 1888
  - Lowell, MA (Box 1, Folder 14)
    M-L-1 Lowell MA, Boott Mill, 1835
    M-L-1a Lowell MA, Suffolk Mill #6, 1831
  - Manchaug, MA; Meteun, MA (Box 1, Folder 15)
    M-M-1 Manchaug MA, BBR Knight Cotton Mill, 1850
    M-M-3 Meteun MA, Metheun Co., 1826
  - North Billerica, MA (Box 1, Folder 16)
    M-N-1 North Billerica MA
    M-N-1a North Billerica MA
  - North Uxbridge, MA (Box 1, Folder 17)
    M-N-2 North Uxbridge MA, Crown and Eagle Mill, 1825
  - Newbury Port, MA; North Adams, MA; Northampton, MA (Box 1, Folder 18)
    M-N-5 Newbury Port MA, James Steam Mill, 1842
    M-N-6 North Adams MA, mill known as Cascade Co.
    M-N-7 Northampton MA
  - North Andover, MA; Southbridge, MA (Box 1, Folder 19)
    M-N-4 North Andover MA, North Andover Mills, 1825
    M-S-1b Southbridge MA, mill
  - Thorndike, MA; Uxbridge, MA (Box 1, Folder 20)
    M-T-1 Thorndike MA, mill
    M-U-1 Uxbridge MA, mill known as Scott's Woolen Mill
  - Whitinsville, MA (Box 1, Folder 21)
    M-W-1 Whitinsville MA (Northbridge), Northbridge Mfg/Whitinsville Cotton, 1846
    M-W-1a Whitinsville MA (Northbridge), Whitin's Mill/Wilkinson Mill, 1826
    M-W-2 Whitinsville MA (Northbridge), Linwood Mill, 1870
  - Biddeford, ME; Berwick, ME (Box 1, Folder 22)
    ME-B-1 Biddeford ME, Pepperell Mill, 1848
    ME-N-1 N. Berwick ME, N. Berwick Mill, n.d
  - Ashland, NH; Claremont, NH (Box 2, Folder 23)
    N-A-1 Ashland NH, 1840, 1880
    N-C-1 Claremont NH, Monadock Mill, 1836
  - Dover, NH; Franklin, NH (Box 2, Folder 24)
    N-D-1 Dover NH, Sawyer's Mills, 1824
    N-D-1a Dover NH, Cocheco Mfg Co., 1919
    N-F-1 Franklin NH, mill
  - Harrisville, NH (Box 2, Folder 25)
    N-H-1 Harrisville N.H., Harris Mill 1832, Cheshire Mill, 1846
  - Harrisville, NH (Box 2, Folder 26)
    N-H-1 Harrisville NH
  - Hillsborough, NH (Box 2, Folder 27)
    N-H-2 Hillsborough NH, Contocook Mills 1845-1865
  - Jaffrey, NH; Keene, NH (Box 2, Folder 28)
    N-J-1 Jaffrey NH, Stone Brothers and Curtis Mill, 1872
    N-K-1 Keene NH, Faulkner and Colongy Mill, 1838
  - Laconia, NH (Box 2, Folder 29)
    N-L-1 Laconia NH, Belknap 1823, Busiel Mills, 1853
    N-L-1a Laconia NH, Belknap 1823, Busiel Mills, 1853
  - Manchester, NH (Box 2, Folder 30)
    N-M-1 Manchester NH, Amoskeag Mills, 1838
  - Newmarket, NH; Somersworth, NH; Salmon Falls (Box 2, Folder 31)
    N-N-1 Newmarket NH, Newmarket Mfg. Co., 1823
    N-S-1 Somersworth NH, Great Falls MFG Co., 1821
    N-S-2 Salmon Falls, Salmon Falls Mill, 1822
  - Nashua, NH; New Ipswich, NH; Newport, NH (Box 2, Folder 32)
    N-N-2 Nashua NH, Nashua Mfg. Co., 1825
    N-N-3 New Ipswich NH, Columbian Mfg. Co., 1875
    N-N-4 Newport NH, Dexter Richards and Sons Mill, 1905
  - Suncook, NH; Tilton, NH (Box 2, Folder 33)
    N-S-3 Suncook NH, China Mill, 1867
    N-T-1 Tilton NH, Winnisquam Mill, 1868
  - Cohoes, NY (Box 2, Folder 34)
    NY-C-1 Cohoes NY, Harmony Mills, 1826
  - Ashton, RI; Albion, RI; Arctic, RI (Box 2, Folder 35)
    R-A-1 Ashton RI, Ashton Mill, 1867
    R-A-2 Albion RI, Albion Mill, 1830
    R-A-3 Arctic RI, Arctic Mill, 1852
  - Carolina, RI (Box 2, Folder 36)
    R-C-1 Carolina RI, Mill, 1841
  - Carolina, RI (Box 2, Folder 37)
    R-C-1 Carolina RI
  - Central Falls, RI (Box 2, Folder 38)
    R-C-2 Central Falls RI, Central Falls Woolen Co., 1865
    R-C-2a Central Falls RI, Kennedy-Stafford Mill, 1824
    R-C-2b Central Falls RI, Pawtucket Hair Cloth, 1864
    R-C-2c Central Falls RI, Pawtucket Thread Mfg., 1825
    R-C-2d Central Falls RI, U.S. Cotton Co., 1861
  - Chepachet, RI; Coventry, RI (Box 2, Folder 39)
    R-C-3 Chepachet RI, Chepachet Mill, 1814
    R-C-5 Coventry RI, Harris Mill, 1850
    R-C-5a Coventry RI, Anthony Mills, 1810-73
  - Greenwich, RI; Exeter, RI (Box 2, Folder 40)
    R-E-1 E. Greenwich RI, Bay Mill, 1840
    R-E-2 Exeter RI, Lawton Mill, 1830
  - Fiskville, RI; Forestdale, RI (Box 2, Folder 41)
    R-F-1 Fiskville RI, Fiskville worker cottages, 1810-15
    R-F-2 Forestdale RI, Stamina Mill, 1860
  - Georgiaville, RI (Box 2, Folder 42)
    R-G-1 Georgiaville RI (Smithfield), Georgiaville Mill, 1853
    R-G-2 Georgiaville RI (Smithfield), Pooke + Steere Mill 1846
  - Hope, RI; Harrisville, RI (Box 2, Folder 43)
    R-H-2 Hope RI, mills, 1807-1844
    R-H-3 Harrisville RI, mill #4, 1911
    R-H-3a Harrisville RI, mill, n.d.
  - Lippitt, RI (Box 2, Folder 44)
    R-L-1 Lippitt RI (W. Warwick), Lippitt Mill, 1809
  - North Providence, RI (Box 2, Folder 45)
    R-N-1 North Providence RI, Allendale Mill, 1822
  - N. Kingston, RI (Box 2, Folder 46)
    R-N-3 N. Kingston RI, Hamilton Web Co., 1866
    R-N-3a N. Kingston RI, Lafayette Mill, 1877
    R-N-3b N. Kingston RI, Shady Lea Mill, 1820
  - Olneyville, RI (Box 2, Folder 47)
    R-O-1 Olneyville RI (North Providence), Atlantic Mills, 1851
    R-P-1 Pascoag RI, Sayles Mill, 1865
  - Pawtucket, RI (Box 2, Folder 48)
    R-P-2 Pawtucket RI, Old Slater Mill, 1793
    R-P-2a Pawtucket RI, Conant Thread, 1860
    R-P-2b Pawtucket RI, Wilkinson Mill, 1810
  - Phenix, RI; Potter Hill, RI (Box 2, Folder 49)
    R-P-3 Phenix RI, Phenix Mill, 1821
    R-P-4 Potter Hill RI, Potter Hill Mills, 1835
  - Providence, RI (Box 2, Folder 50)
    R-P-5 Providence RI, Dyersville Mill, 1845
    R-P-5b Providence RI, Merino Mills, 1851
    R-P-5c Providence RI, Allen Print Works, 1830
  - Peacedale, RI; Quidnick, RI (Box 2, Folder 51)
    R-P-6 Peacedale RI, mills, 1847
    R-Q-1 Quidnick RI, mills, 1848
  - Riverpoint, RI; Rockville, RI; Slaterville, RI (Box 2, Folder 52)
    R-R-1 Riverpoint RI, Green-Royal Mill, 1890-1919
    R-R-2 Rockville RI, mills, 1844
    R-S-1 Slaterville RI, Slaterville Cotton Mill, 1826
  - Shannock, RI; Kingston, RI (Box 3, Folder 53)
    R-S-2 Shannock RI (Richmond), Shannock Mill, 1848
    R-S-3 S. Kingston RI, Glen Rock Mill, after 1840
    R-S-3a S. Kingston RI, Wakefield Woolen, 1820
    R-S-3b S. Kingston RI, Rodman Mill, 1843
  - West Warwick, RI; Warwick, RI (Box 3, Folder 54)
    R-W-3 West Warwick RI, Centerville Mills, 1807
    R-W-3a West Warwick RI, Crompton Mills, 1807
    R-W-5 Warwick RI, Pontiac Mills 1863
  - Woonsocket, RI (Box 3, Folder 55)
    R-W-1 Woonsocket RI, Ballou-Lippitt Mill, 1836
    R-W-1b Woonsocket RI, Jencks Mill, 1822
    R-W-1c Woonsocket RI, Bernon Mills, 1827
    R-W-1e Woonsocket RI, Harris Mill #2, 1840
  - White Rocket, RI; Westerly, RI (Box 3, Folder 56)
    R-W-2 White Rock RI (Westerly), White Rock Mill, 1849
    R-W-4 Westerly RI, Stillmanville Mill, 1848
  - Bennington, VT (Box 3, Folder 57)
    V-B-1 Bennington VT, Valentine Mill, 1824
    V-B-1a Bennington VT, Bradford Mill
    V-B-1b Bennington VT, Holden + Leonard Mill
    V-B-1c Bennington VT, Thompson Mfg.
    V-B-1d Bennington VT, Cooper Knitting Mill
  - Ludlow, VT (Box 3, Folder 58)
    V-L-1 Ludlow VT, Graymont Woolen Co.
  - Non-Textile Factories (Box 3, Folder 59)
    Non-Textile Factories
  - Northampton Project (Box 3, Folder 60)
    CVH Northampton Project
  - Cotton Hollow Work (Box 3, Folder 61)
    Cotton Hollow Work
  - Mill Towns Research (Box 3, Folder 62)
    Mill Towns Research
- Series II. Negatives
  - 35 mm negatives. 1967-68--Holyoke-Hartford; 1970--Manchester, UK; 1981-82--Textile Mills
    - Envelope Hartford-Holyoke 1967-68 (Box 16)
      24 negative sleves
    - Envelope Factories Willimantic, CT; Rhode Island, April 1982 (Binder 1)
      6 negative sleeves
    - Envelope Factories August 1981 (Binder 1)
      3 negative sleeves
    - Envelope Hartford-Holyoke 1968-69 (Binder 1)
      39 negative sleeves
    - Envelope Factories Fall 1981; August-beginning of mill project 1981 (Binder 1)
      16 negative sleeves
    - Trip 1 Factories Aug. 1982--Mass, N.H., Maine (Binder 1)
      22 negative sleeves
    - Envelope Manchester, England 1970-71 (Binder 1)
      9 negative sleeves
    - Envelope Aug-Sept 1982, Holyoke, MA; Harrisville, NH (Binder 1)
    - Envelope Factories March and April 1982, Connecticut + R.I. (Binder 1)
      21 negative sleeves
    - Envelope Trip 2 Factories, Conn., R.I., Fall River, Aug. 1982 (Binder 1)
      13 negative sleeves
    - Envelope Mystery Mills Circa 1982, includes other negatives 1980's (Binder 1)
    - Envelope Baltic, CT; Putnam, CT; Exeter, E. Greenwich, Pontiac Mills, Pooketsteere, RI Nov. 1982 (Binder 1)
    - Envelope Factories Bennington, Cohoes, N.Y; Rockville, Phoenixville, Taftville, CT May-July 1982 (Binder 1)
      19 negative sleeves
    - Envelope Factories Lowel area, MA March 1982 (Binder 1)
      10 negative sleeves
    - Envelope Factories MA, CT, RI, Jan. 1982 (Binder 1)
      15 negative sleeves
  - Binder 1: Negative book 1, 1982-1989
    - 8201 March, 1982; MA: Newbury Port; Textile mill (Binder 1)
      1 sheet, 12 negatives
    - 8202 August, 1982; MA: Fall River; Textile mills and burned ruins (Binder 1)
      1 sheet, 14 negatives
    - 8203 August, 1982; RI: Woonsockett; Textile mills; fine shot of Harris Mill (Binder 1)
    - 8204 September, 1982; NH: Hillsborough; Textile mills and general store; excellent images (Binder 1)
    - 8205 NH: Harrisville; August, 1982; Textile mills; good images (Binder 1)
      1 sheet, 13 negatives
    - 8206 August, 1982; NH: Newmarket, Dover; Textile mills, row housing; Great shot of mills on Salmon River (Binder 1)
    - 8207 December, 1982; CT: Rockville; Textile mills, Rock Mfg. (Binder 1)
    - 8301 January, 1983; CT: Oxoboxo River area; textile mills, ruins, complex along Oxoboxo (Binder 1)
      1 sheet, 11 negatives
    - 8302 January, 1983; MA: Manchaug; textile mills (Binder 1)
    - 8303 January, 1983; MA: Manchaug, Wittinsville; textile mills (Binder 1)
    - 8304 January, 1983; RI: Carolina; textile mills and mill village (Binder 1)
    - 8305 January, 1983; MA: North Uxbridge; textile mills, Crown and Eagle; includes burned mills (Binder 1)
      1 sheet, 15 negatives
    - 8306 January, 1983; RI: Woonsockett; Stamina Mill; Includes Grafton, MA (Binder 1)
    - 8307 February, 1983; CT: Waterbury, MA: Grafton; textile mills (Binder 1)
    - 8308 February, 1983; CT: Quinebaug, N. Grosvenordale; textile mills (Binder 1)
    - 8309 February, 1983; CT: Putnam, Beacon Falls; textile mills (Binder 1)
    - 8310 March, 1983; MA: Hinsdale; textile mills (Binder 1)
    - 8311 April, 1983; RI: Providence area; textile mills, Dyersville, Allendale (Binder 1)
      1 sheet, 10 negatives
    - 8312 April, 1982; RI: Providence area; textile mills, Lippitt, Harris, includes housing (Binder 1)
    - 8313 April, 1983; RI: Pawtuckett; textile mills, Slater, Wilkinson (Binder 1)
    - 8314 May, 1983; RI: Kingston; Textile mills, Hamilton Web, double clerestory mill (Binder 1)
    - 8315 June, 1983; MA: Housatonic, CT: Oxoboxo, textile mills (Binder 1)
    - 8316June, 1983; RI: Shady Lea, Oxoboxo area; textile mills; includes East Hampton, CT (Binder 1)
    - 8317 June, 1983; CT: Norwich area; textile mills, Yantic Woolen mill (Binder 1)
    - 8318 August, 1983; NH: Claremont; textile mills; includes some VT mills (Binder 1)
    - 8319 November, 1983; RI: Cranston; textile mills; includes Pontiac complex (Binder 1)
      1 sheet, 15 sheets
    - 8320 November, 1983; MA: Chicopee, Holyoke; textile mills, housing; includes gate, walkway over tracks (Binder 1)
    - 8321 November, 1983; MA: Holyoke, Chicopee; textile mills, housing (Binder 1)
    - 8401 February, 1984; MA: Holyoke; textile mills, housing (Binder 1)
    - 8402 March, 1984; CT: Thomaston; Vernacular, Opera House, train station (Binder 1)
    - 8403 June, 1984; MA: Witinsville; textile mills; includes Gilbert Clock factory, Winsted, CT (Binder 1)
    - 8404 June, 1984; PA: Philadelphia area; textile mills; very high contrast (Binder 1)
    - 8405 June, 1984; PA: Rockville; textile mills (Binder 1)
    - 8406 June, 1984; NJ: Patterson; textile mills, silk mills (Binder 1)
      13 negatives
    - 8407 June, 1884; MA, RI; textile mills, Pontoosic Mill (Binder 1)
    - 8408 July, 1884; CT: western towns; houses, doorways (Binder 1)
    - 8409 August, 1884; MA, Salem area; houses, churches; Old Ship Meeting House (Binder 1)
      2 sheets, 18 negatives
    - 8410 September, 1884; CT: Bristol; Vernacular, Lake Compounce; Amusement Park; includes roller coaster (Binder 1)
    - 8411 September, 1984; NH; textile mills; high contrast (Binder 1)
    - 8412 September, 1984; NH; textile mills, Jaffrey area; high contrast (Binder 1)
    - 8501 June, 1985; CT: N. Grosvenordale; milltowns, includes Torrington diner (Binder 1)
    - 8701 January, 1987; CT: N. Grosvenordale; milltowns (Binder 1)
    - 8702 November, 1987; MA: Western hills; Vernacular, sugar house (Binder 1)
    - 8801 June, 1988; CT: Beacon Falls, ME; Vernacular, Millstowns; includes carousel animals, ME (Binder 1)
    - 8902 April, 1989; CT: Eastern towns, N. Grovenordale; milltowns, housing (Binder 1)
      1 sheet, 16 negatives
    - 8901 April, 1989; CT: Willimantic; textile mills, American Thread (Binder 1)
    - 8903 October, 1989; NY: Cohoes, CT: Hartford; Textile mills; includes Royal Typewriter Factory (Binder 1)
    - 8905 August, 1989; NB, NS Canada; Rural vernacular (Binder 1)
    - 8904 August, 1989; NB Canada; Urban vernacular; St. John's (Binder 1)
    - 8906 Agust, 1989; NB Canada, ME; Urban vernacular (Binder 1)
    level="file">
  - Binder 2: Negative book 2, 1990-1996
    - 9001 September, 1990; NA: Pittsfield; Urban vernacular; stores, Masonic Lodge (Binder 1)
    - 9002 October, 1990; NY: Saratoga; Vernacular, urban and rural; *includes Clifton Park Hotel (Binder 1)
    - 9101 February, 1991; CT: Glastonbury; Textile mills, roadside vernacular; Includes Cotton Hollow, steam shovel (Binder 1)
    - 9102 February, 1991; CT: Deep River, East Haddam; Rural vernacular, milltowns; *includes Deep River doorways (Binder 1)
    - 9103 August, 1991; NY: Tonawanda, Rte. 20; roadside vernacular; *includes cabins on Rte. 20 (Binder 1)
    - 9104 August-September, 1991; VT: Bellows Falls, MA; CT River, houses; *includes bridge at Bellows Falls (Binder 1)
    - 9105 October, 1991; CT: Glastonbury, Portland, Old Saybrook; houses, vernacular (Binder 1)
    - 9106 October, November, 1991; RI: Newport, CT: Suffield; houses (Binder 1)
    - 9107 November 3, 1991; CT: Suffield, Windsor; houses; *includes the Kent Place (Binder 1)
    - 9108 November, 1991; MA: Deerfield, Westfield; houses, vernacular; includes CT Valley doorways, honey house (Binder 1)
      1 sheet, 15 megatives
    - 9109 November 3, 1991; MA: Westfield; houses, roadside vernacular; *includes honey house (Binder 1)
    - 9201 March, 1992; MA: Southampton, Westfield; houses, vernacular; includes Southampton Grange (Binder 1)
    - 9202 June, 1992; CT: hartford, MA: Feeding Hills Mills, vernacular; Royal Typewriter Factory, Colt building (Binder 1)
    - 9203 September, 1992; VT: Windsor; Milltowns (Binder 1)
    - 9204 October, 1992; RI, VT: Bellows Falls; rural vernacular, CT River; very good light (Binder 1)
    - 9205 October, November, 1992; RI, CA: San Diego; houses, landscape (Binder 1)
    - 9206 November, 1992; CA: San Diego, Mexico; urban and roadside vernacular (Binder 1)
    - 9207 November, 1992; CA: San Diego; landscape, urban vernacular (Binder 1)
    - 9208 November, 1992; CA: San Diego, mexico; roadside vernacular (Binder 1)
    - 9301 January, 1993; MA: Uxbridge; milltowns (Binder 1)
    - 9302 January, 1993; MA: Uxbridge; textile mills (Binder 1)
    - 9303 January, March, 1993; MA: Uxbridge area, Granville; milltowns, houses; includes Highway bridge (Binder 1)
      1 sheet, 9 negatives
    - 9304 May 1993; CT: Granby; rural vernacular; tobacco farms, barns (Binder 1)
    - 9305 June, 1993; NY: Chataqua; vernacular (Binder 1)